Gabriel Chan. Jarvis Consulting

I graduated from University of Toronto as a Computer Science Specialist in 2021 and obtained a Bachelor's degree in this subject. During this time, I learned how to use a wide range of programming languages like Python, Java and C. I was also introduced to new technologies such as Unity and Postman and I was assigned many group projects where I learned how to collaborate with others effectively. I joined Jarvis in October where I was further trained in how to use new technologies such as Docker, Maven and JDBC and how to build programs in an effective and efficient manner. While I learned about how to use these tools, Jarvis also taught me about many effective programming practices such as the Scrum framework, Test-Driven Development as well as Continuous Integration.

Skills

Proficient: Java, Python, C, Agile/Scrum, SQLCompetent: Bash, Unity, Maven, Git, Docker

Familiar: HTML, Javascript, Azure, React, Spring

Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis_data_eng_GabrielChan

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: The Jarvis Linux Cluster Administration manages about 10 nodes each using the CentOS 7 Linux distribution. These nodes are also connected through a switch and are able to communicate using internal IPv4 addresses. The purpose of this project is to track and record the performance of each node as well as the resources each node uses. This data will be stored in an RDBMS database and used to generate reports for plans regarding future nodes.

Core Java Apps [GitHub]:

- Grep App: This application, given a regular expression, a directory and an output file, will read each file in the given directory (including in sub-directories) and return lines that match the given regular expression. Notable classes that were used include the Pattern class for matching lines with regular expression as well as the BufferedReader, BufferedWriter and nio.Files class for reading and writing files. There is also a lambda implementation which focuses more on using lambda functions and the Stream class. The IntelliJ IDE was used to write this application and Docker was used for deployment.
- JDBC App: This application interacts with a PostgreSQL database to perform CRUD operations. Java Database Connectivity provides the framework for interacting with the database. Operations are performed using the JDBCExecutor class and the Data Access Object outlined in CustomerDAO. Maven was used to help construct the project and install the necessary dependencies.
- Twitter CRUD App: The Twitter CRUD app accesses the user's Twitter account through a set of key and secret tokens and sends HTTP requests to perform CRUD operations using Twitter's REST API. This application allows the user to create, retrieve and delete Tweets using a command line interface. Core technologies used in the implementation of this application include, OAuth, Google GSON, Mockito, JUnit, Maven and Docker.

Highlighted Projects

Trash Panda Unity Project [GitHub]: Developed a Unity video game alongside peers including fellow developers, artists, animators and composers. The players takes the role of a raccoon mom causing as much damage as possible to a construction site in an effort to protect her children. I designed the artificial intelligence of enemies (construction workers) and designed a handful of UI elements.

Professional Experiences

Software Developer, Jarvis (October, 2021 - February, 2022, June, 2022 - present): Designed back end of multiple projects. Participated in Scrum meetings with peers daily and at the end of each sprint.

Quality Assurance Analyst, National Bank of Canada (February,2022 - June,2022): Designed and executed tests to ensure proper performance of web applications. Participated in Scrum meetings with peers daily and at the end of each sprint.

Education

University of Toronto (2013 - 2020), Honours Bachelor of Science, Computer Science - GPA: 2.92/4.0

Miscellaneous

- Video Games
- Anime TV shows